Evan Heisler

FRONTEND ENGINEER

CONTACT

evanheisler@gmail.com https://evanheisler.com

Crosslake, Minnesota 612-743-9929

SKILLS

Core Competencies

Javascript, Client-side Frameworks,
ReactJS, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Wordpress,
Wireframing, Prototyping, API
Integration, Web Standards, Accessibility,
Web Application Architecture and
Development

Stack Experience

Ruby on Rails, Python, NodeJS, Apache, NGINX, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, PHP

Leadership

Technical Lead, Mentor, Team Lead, Client Relations, Documentation, QA, Backlog Management, Storywriting, Acceptance Criteria

Miscellaneous

Git, Mercurial, Asana, Jira, Docker, Vagrant, Agile, Lean, Human-Centered Design, Sketch, Invision

OTHER

In 2017, I founded Heisler Studio. When not writing code, I design and build my own furniture and home goods in an effort to introduce good design and thoughtful experience in the real world. I use my technology experience to create 3-D models as well as logistics tools.

I am motivated by social responsibility, the environment and bringing civility to the world through technology.

SUMMARY

More than 12 years of experience building and maintaining web products in a variety of roles and industries. Experience-based learner and self starter adept at client-side web development and interaction design. Capable of seeing features through from conception, execution, and beyond.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Merged the gap between user experience design and application development
Combined Multi-disciplinary roles in experience and development
Addressed Multi-lingual and Accessibility requirements effectively
Advocated for technical lead role to assist in translating business requirements into actionable development stories and requirements gathering
Modeled an improved pull request using graphics and animations
Persuaded the use of client-side frameworks in traditional MVC stacks
Guided the use of acceptance criteria during storywriting
Elicited qualitative strategy from quantitative story writing sessions
Achieved Long lasting client relationships
Strengthened autonomous work ethos
Assisted Intern leadership

WORK HISTORY

SOFTWARE FOR GOOD

GREER & ASSOCIATES

MINNESOTA SEA GRANT

Interactive Producer

Communications Designer

JOI I WARE TOR GOOD	April 2015 - Tresent
Web Application Engineer & Senior Experience Developer	
DIGITARIA (now Mirum) User Experience Consultant	2013
RED STAMP (acquired mobile startup)	2012
UX/UI Consultant, Frontend Developer	
WORKSIMPLE (startup) Senior Experience Designer	2011
GOKART LABS	2009 - 2011
Web Developer / Experience Architect	2009 - 2011
THORN CREATIVE	2008 - 2009
Web Developer	

April 2013 - Present

2008

2006 - 2007

Evan Heisler

FRONTEND ENGINEER

CONTACT

evanheisler@gmail.com https://evanheisler.com

Crosslake, Minnesota 612-743-9929

PROJECTS OF NOTE

VALIMAIL

Description: Staff augmentation role to assist on a suite of products related to e-mail security in feature development as well as converting a hybrid application to a fully ReactJS clientside and Pails backend

Environment: Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, Docker, PostgreSQL, Jira

Key Achievements:

Refactor, rewrite and update legacy codebase

Contribute extensible components to a component library for use across products

Augment a Bay Area colocated team as a remote resource

SECOND HARVEST FOOD BANK

Description: Developed a logistics and management tool for a large scale food bank

Environment: Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, Docker, Azure, PostgreSQL

Key Achievements

Developed heavy lifting ReactJS application

Integration with multiple external sources, primarily a Rails JSON API

Live prototyping and UX design

Translate client feedback into stories and acceptance criteria

FAIR TRADE USA PRICE RISK MANAGEMENT SIMULATOR

Description: Developed a web based simulation tool to assist Coffee cooperatives in Central and South America in employing a futures/options hedging strategy

Environment: Python, ReactJS, Platform.sh, PostgreSQL, Victory Charts

Key Achievements

Lead designer and frontend developer

Assisted client in conveying difficult subject matter in a safe and approachable manner

Integrates to live market data Complex data visualizations

Multilingual

HOUSING HUB APPLICANT APPLICATION

Description: Platform for users to browse, apply, and manage the process for finding quality,

low income housing.

Environment: Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, PostgreSQL

Key Achievements:

Manage a complex client-side application process

WCAG 2.0 & 508 Compliance

Instrumental in improving user experience through interaction design

SAFESPACE DATA DASHBOARD

Description: Developed a dashboard to report on data collected from the mobile applications, which are used to capture real-time information about police incidents.

Environment: iOS application, Firebase, ReactJS, Victory Charts

Key Achievements:

Developed a dashboard for displaying statistics captured by mobile app

Complex data parsing and data visualizations of captured data

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA DULUTH

BFA, Graphic Design

Followed core curriculum in a deep study of art & design

Branched out into elective credits and independent study to explore web development

Core member of Student Design Organization working with real clients

Began working professionally as a designer prior to graduating while also freelancing as a web developer

UNIVERSITY OF OTAGO, NEW ZEALAND

Study Abroad

Studied graphic design and web development and gained immeasurable insight into an industry spanning the globe